Rowe Morehouse rm@tephra.tech • (541) 640-9592

Sales Executive, Developer Advocate, Technical Writer, Frontend Dev, and Expert Digital Marketer w/ Master's degree & certifications from Amazon AWS, Salesforce, Google, Qualtrics, Meta.

I'm hands-on technical but also very experienced in B2B & SaaS sales, sales management, sales enablement, & sales culture.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Principal Consultant / Founder — Trendara LLC 2009 - Present

15 years of successful consulting & execution for all types of Software, Product Dev, Technical Writing, & Internet Marketing projects! Everyday \$\$\$ cash flow + happy customers. Trendara is a digital marketing agency specializing in B2B technology and financial services clients.

- Created keyword campaigns for marketing VMWare products to developers. My copywriting and AdWords optimization reduced cost-per-lead by 37% while increasing lead volume at the same time.
 Managed their \$400k AdWords spend.
- Identified new traffic sources and implemented landing-page A/B testing experiments that increased a Financial Services client's leads by over 600% — with conversion rates as high as 23%.
- Drove the overall value proposition and product marketing vision for a Fintech startup, resulting in a \$500k VC seed round, and over \$500k in initial sales.
- Identified new traffic sources & implemented landing-page A/B testing experiments that increased a Financial Services client's lead volume by over 600% with conversion rates as high as 23%.
- Totally rewrote the Sales Playbook for a \$100MM SaaS company and trained their team of 12 inside sales reps on how to best sell the product to their target audience.

Director of Marketing - RampRate 2008 - 2009

Developed B2B marketing programs to sell cloud services to VP and C-Suite decision-makers. Wrote content for all touchpoints in the Buyer's Journey. Set up Salesforce.com and aligned the marketing group and sales team on a lead generation process.

MORE 🕕

Sales Manager / Founder — Wildwood Hills Search Marketing 2004 - 2009

Founded this successful business-to-consumer internet advertising agency & grew it to over 200 clients via a productized service offering and a formalized sales strategy.

Origin Story: After 2 years selling web advertising for other firms, I realized that many businesses at that time didn't understand the value of online marketing. Business Owners really wanted phone calls from new prospects - so I incorporated an LLC & launched the world's first Pay-Per-Call performance marketing service.

- Architected a toll free phone call-tracking system using open source software and spreadsheets. I also built an automated billing system that integrated with authorize.net payment gateway.
- The key to the success of this business was my sales management & coaching skills, the smart sales playbook & sales collateral I developed, and my motivating commission structure which attracted top salespeople who I hired and managed. I'm also fun to work with!

Sales Executive — Web Media Online Advertising 2003 - 2005

- Direct Sales. We take Visa, Mastercard, and American Express ... which will it be?
- Sold all manner of SEM / SEO / PPC / CPA / CPM internet advertising media as an independent rep for multiple firms in LA and SF. Purchased traffic at a discount and ran my own affiliate offers.

Online Marketing Specialist — Warner Bros. Online 2001 - 2003

I was hired for hands-on viral marketing of major motion pictures like The Matrix, Harry Potter & Scooby Doo. Generated millions of impressions for these global brands, contributing to gross sales around release dates.

Technical Project Manager — Razorfish 1998 - 2001

- Managed cross-functional, multi-disciplinary project teams for web development engagements w/budgets ranging from \$1 to \$3 million. Full accountability for cost / schedule / quality for the client - and overall P&L for the agency - which required a comprehensive understanding of financial and operational metrics and levers.
- Learned the necessary soft-skills to motivate team members when you have all the responsibility, and no direct authority. Learned to clarify ambiguous requirements, identify hidden stakeholders, and influence client decisions.
- Implemented project risk-identification practices & change control procedures. Implemented the best parts of Agile, Scrum, PMI PMBOK, and Rational Unified methodologies.

Senior Web Developer — Move.com 1996 - 1998

HTML / CSS / JavaScript. Vested + IPO during my tenure.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree — Integrated Marketing Communications

University of Colorado Boulder - 3.8 GPA

Bachelor's Degree — Studies in Social Psychology & Computer Science

UC Santa Cruz – Completed degree in 2 years, age 20. Graduated with Honors. 🧩

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect (Associate) — Amazon Web Services

Hands-on cloud networking, storage, database, and systems architecture. Strong understanding of software development life cycle, web & app servers, serverless, the API economy.

Salesforce Certified Sales Cloud Consultant - Salesforce.com

Trained in client-facing discovery of business goals & challenges in order to design and implement Sales Cloud and Marketing Cloud solutions. Requires a deep knowledge of business processes & technical architecture of complex SaaS. Also requires interpersonal acumen and emotional intelligence to navigate the opinions of high-profile stakeholders.

Google AdWords & Analytics Certifications – Google

Mastery of building and optimizing profitable Google CPC and CPA advertising campaigns; including search, display, YouTube, and contextual. Advanced traffic and user behavior analysis using segmentation, cohort, channel, churn, and audience reports.

PUBLICATIONS & VOLUNTEER WORK

Author, ClickBank Ebook – 7th Edition published: Feb, 2022

Self-published an Ebook that **has grossed a cumulative \$1.7 million in passive revenue**; 100% due to my evolving product roadmap, persuasive copywriting, obsessive customer focus, and automated PPC & email marketing efforts

Lead Instructor — ChickTech — 2018 - Present

I teach beginning web development to young people for this 501©(3) supporting women and girls in tech. My latest workshop is teaching them Markdown to write Github READMEs.

REFERENCES & MORE

"Rowe's skills on the PM side were top notch. He understands technology and is great at motivating teams, a rare combination. He also contributed deep thinking on design and creative sides." — **Ken Manning, CEO at Outpost**

"Rowe is a high energy salesman with a book full of contacts. He is a motivator, and an innovator with creative strategies to build business. He loves to learn and to share his knowledge." — **Donnie Ginkus, Enterprise Cloud Sales at Oracle**

"Whatever the situation or subject matter, Rowe always has something insightful to add to the mix. A thorough self-starter, he also has the ability to take those ideas and turn them into products and services. Faced with a new challenge, Rowe will focus and absorb the necessary information, develop an informed perspective, and deliver a solution which hits the mark. I can count on him to ask smart questions and give smarter answers." — Matt Zimmerman, Director of Engineering at DoorDash

"Rowe is in his third year volunteering for ChickTech and has helped lead both in-person and virtual workshops for ChickTech's High School program. Rowe's latest workshop had some AMAZING student feedback. He broke down the steps clearly and made the content accessible and clear to students of all skill levels. I'm looking forward to having Rowe back again!" — Kerstin Motsch-Reiter, National Programs Manager at ChickTech

Go to https://git.io/rowemore to see my work samples, chat with me online, access my socials, see a complete list of my software tools & more!

Keywords: Developer Relations · DevRel · Developer Evangelist · Developer Evangelism · Developer Advocate · Developer Advocacy · Developer Marketing · Developer Success · Developer Experience · DX · Content Creator · Content Development · Content Developer · Technical Writing · Technical Writer · Technology Writer · Software Documentation · Documentation Writer · Ghostwriting · Ghostwriter · Copywriting · Copywriter · Ecommerce Writer · UX Writer · UX Writing · Public Speaking · Presenting · Presentations Direct Sales · Inside Sales · Sales Rep · Sales Representative · Sales Exec · Sales Exec · Sales Executive · Technical Sales · Software Sales · Sales Enablement · Sales Management